놈들이 의료검사로내가 베스가 아닌걸 알았다고
우리 DNA가 동일하다고니가 그랬잖아
그런거거든있잖아 어쩜
니 해맑은 성격이법칙을 날려버렸는지
젠장 매기 첸은또 누구야?
베스가 쏜 여자야
매기가 널 만드는걸도왔었어
그러다 빛을 봤지
우릴 보호하려고베스가 그여잘 죽인거네
아트, 이것 좀 봐야돼피해자 지문 일치하는게 나왔어
젠장 생긴건 왜 베스랑똑같은거야?
폴은.. 자기 담당자올리비에한테 보고해
자넨 쉬면서치료나 받게
더 빨리
코지마의 안전이위험한 상태야
저기, 자기 자신에대해서만
생물학 검사를한게 아니라
여덟명이 더있다는걸..알아냈더군요
그이가내 감시자 같거든
내가 그애 진짜 감시자를집어낸거 같거든
내 인생을망쳐놓고 싶은거야?
내가 널망쳐버려 주겠어
나 도니랑 이혼하고싶지 않아
근데, 계속 거짓말할 수도 없어
그럼 말해버리면어떻까?
쇼반, 이쪽은
앨리슨 헨드릭스에요
아줌마는 무슨 일이있었어요?
나도 몰라
키아라! 키아라!안돼!
7세 여아차량에 치었음
GCS 3*글라우스 혼수상태 등급
가슴에 중상내출혈이 가능성
정신차려, 얘야, 제발3분후 도착 예정
우리가 같이 있거든사랑해, 다들 있어
등록하고3번실로 옮겨
우리 여깄어, 제발잠시만요, 잠시만요
더는 못 들어가세요
안돼, 안돼, 안돼!
사라, 사라
저분들 일하시게해드려야지
셋에 간다하나, 둘, 셋!
초음파, 외상검사해야겠어
흉부, 골반, 목뒤준비되면 1단계부터해
또 응급카트 준비하고삽관을 해야될꺼야
수술실이 준비됐어요좋아
헬레나가 우릴 찾아낼꺼란생각을 했어야했는데
걜 막았어야만했어요
스스로를 탓하는건그만 두려무나
네가 이런건아니잖니
애는 괜찮을꺼야사라
그래야지
제가 커피 좀갖다 드릴까요?
앨리슨,무슨 뜻인지 알아
진짜로지금은 그냥..
음, 알았어, 알았어방해 안할께
그래
내가 도움은안되지만
내 딸이 저깄단생각이 들거든
집에 가는게 좋겠다
가서 잠 좀 자둬
나 집에 못가필릭스. 나..
내 감시자를때려줬거든
사라처럼 얼굴에 봉지를뒤집어쓰고
신만 아는 어디로실려갈꺼야
알았어
그럼내 집으로 가
알았어, 고마워
뭐라도 얘기 나오면연락줄께
갈께
초음파 나왔어요
심장박동은 80
혈압은 80에 50
박사님이것 좀 보세요
어떻게 됐어요?
키아라는괜찮아지리라 봅니다
"봅니다"는무슨 얘기죠?
그게, 진정제를 투여했어요하지만 혈압이나 호흡은
안정을 찾았습니다
갈비뼈에는전혀 손상이 없고요
내출혈도 없으며머리에 외상도 없어요
아이는 괜찮을거같습니다
애가 차에치였었는데
제가 봤다고요
그럼야, 정말 운이좋은 아이네요
괜찮다시잖아
애 괜찮은거야괜찮아, 괜찮다고
애 괜찮다고
우리 아가
한글자막 :  Nike Plus
엄마, 아줌마도똑같이 생겼어요
엄마랑 똑같이생겼어요
쉬, 쉬, 쉬..
자거라우리 원숭이
내가 아줌마한테서지켜줄께
약속할께
여자애가 있었어요
작은 소녀
진정해라, 애야
정신 차려야지
사라가 엄마에요
말도 안되는 소리!
불가능한 일이야
저 때문에 그 아이가차에 치었어요
애는 괜찮아?
그래, 그래바로 잠들었어
그러면, 넌 어떠냐?
이런 행운에감사한 생각 안드니?
전 기적같은거안믿어요
키아라가고무로 되있나봐, 사라
애한텐 행운이였어
의사도 딱그렇게 말하더라
넌 못봤잖아
신에 감사해야지
그리고나서걱정해라
예, 헬레나가사라져야해요
베스 불러올이유가 10개도 넘거든
이봐, 일치하는지문들이 셋이고
그애랑 똑같이 생긴애는뛰어내렸고
이 둘에 관련된쬐만하고 능글거리는
남창도 하나 있지
됐어, 됐다고나도 알아, 앤지..
거기다나,신원미상의 시체도 있지
모든게 거기서시작된거야
100달러 걸깨벡위드가 안면 재구성 끝내면
얘도 그애랑똑같이 생겼을꺼야
아직까진 이렇다할혐의는 없잖아
공무방해이 전부가 민간인 총격
뒤에 일어난거야그래서 뭐?!
그렇단건 그애가 살인자를보호하고 있을 수도 있다는거야
쉬 쉬 쉬 쉬
어떻게 되가나?
여전히 돌파구를찾고 있습니다
그리슨하고 초우가관내에 있었던
칼부림 사건을방금 해결했네
자네들한테도
새로운 관점이 좀필요할거 같은데, 어?
아니요, 괜찮습니다잘되갑니다
오늘 끝날때까지만말미를 좀 주세요
너 내 전파트너를
닭장차에 쳐넣고싶은거야, 응?
내가 틀린거면,
니가 내 마지막 파트너가될꺼야
모르겠네아트
궁금해지기시작하는데
그애가 뭐약점이라도 잡았어?
오늘 마칠때까지앤지
이게 사실이라면
이 아이가정말로 그애의..
어떻게 놓아줄 수있었느냐?
아인 순수해요
말씀하신대로다 했어요..
사라를 이용해서다른 자들한테 접근했죠
그럼 다른 자들은어디있지?!
왜 아직사라가 살아있고?
그자요, 올리비에!
당신을 위해서 제가 그자짐승의 꼬리를 잘랐어요 / 그렇지!
리키 박사의주의를 끌었지!
놈들한텐 아이가가치가 있을꺼다
안돼, 안돼!
그애에요!
여기로 오라고 하거라
말해!
헬레나
키아라는 괜찮아?
만나서 얘기해
너 어디야?
그거 사고였어
말해!
젊은 연인들한테사랑스러운 아파트군
아주 그럴듯해
안됐지만
어제 밤 올리비에가한거짓말 그건 아니지
무슨 거짓말요?
누군가 클럽 신진화에보안기록을 손댔었더군
헌데, 그날밤 그곳에두명의 복제인간이
있었단걸 안다네아닌가?
수년째 잃어버린복제인간을 찾고 있었다네
헬레나, 그애지
나의 흰고래라네폴!
근데 들짐승같지
그애가 자넬속일 리가 없지
베스 흉내를 내다니
여기 지붕 아래서
저 침대에서?
근데, 사라 매닝은가능하지
젠장 뭐야?!
짧게 "고마워"면충분해
그래, 카이라는괜찮아지겠어?
그래, 기적적으로회복했어
잘됐네
어, 어디에, 음..
아, 네..
약이랑 관련된 것들은서랍에 있어
그렇단건 약하는 것들이네 침대 옆에 있었단거지
너 저것도닦았은거야?
지금 우리 애들은엄마집에 있거든
내가 애들한텐위험하니까
그래서 이 집을
나 아파트 찾는 동안
기지로 쓸 수 있을까생각했거든
안되거든!
머, 도니가몇시간 동안은
집을 비워놓고있을테니
난 들려서
옷이랑 잡다한 것들좀 가져와야겠어
좋아!하룻밤만 지내도록해
들어올때 나깨우지만 말아줘
필릭스
나 버림받았거든
혼자서는돌아가지 못하겠어
네가 지원사격 좀해주면 좋겠는데
빌어먹을너 진짜 이럴레?
좀 안될까?
옷 좀갈아입어야겠다
게이스러운 것좀 건네줘
세상에 젠장사라
진짜 다행이다
그래, 의사들도까무러칠뻔했지
니 생각엔 말야키아라가 내 아이라서
특이할 수도있을거 같에?
애한테 상처가없다고 그러는거야?
그래그냥 물어보는 거야
머, 우리가 유전적으로조작된 거라면야
그러니까, 니가 애한테뭔가를 물려줬을 수도 있지
예를 들면?
나도 모르지
도마뱀은 팔다리가다시 자라고
코지마, 키아라는도마뱀이 아니거든
그렇지, 그래
마술은 아니야
줄기세포 때문인데알아?
이봐, 내 옆에서
독일애 DNA 배열을분석하는 애가 있는데
애한테 유전적인 질병이있는지 보라고 할께
네가 원한다면너하고 키아라 표본을
비교해보라고줄 수 있어
에, 나 너한테
유전적인거안줄 꺼거든
니가 델피네한테넘겨줄 수도 있잖아
얘가, 난 우리 합의한대로하고 있다고, 알아?
과학쪽으로쫓아가는거
그래, 그게,
난 과학보다 과학자들을더 신경쓰는 거거든
가야겠다
어, 제가 갈께요
어서와
안녕, 색칠공부랑퍼즐이야
애는 자고 있어
어, S아줌마
여긴 폴이에요
반갑습니다
폴
아줌마도 전부 아셔
머, 분명히전부는 아니구나
저기
날 너무 탓하지말아줘
나쁜 소식이 있어
리키 박사가너 누군지 알아, 사라
놔주세요!
놔줘요!
싫어요!
싫어! 싫어!
모든 걸 너에게 줬는데!
살아갈 이유까지
근데, 보답이..나약함이라니
토마스
아니에요!
니가 그 위조품을보호한다면
너도 그것들보다나은게 없군나
아니야!
그것들과다른게 없어!
리키가 만나고싶어한다고?
자기는 거래를하고싶다고 했어
네가 알고 있단것도 알아서로들 연락하고 있다는 것도
어떻게?코지마가 넘긴거야?
이봐이게 기회라고 생각해
너 딱 그애처럼얘기하네
나도 그사람안믿어
그래도, 지니가병속에서 나왔잖아
놈들한테도그렇지
네 관심사는 한결같잖아답을 얻을 수도 있어
아님 봉지 뒤집어쓰고납치되던가
그사람 만나는데안전한 방법이 있다면?
네 요구대로?
각 표본에서 4천개이상의 염기열을
배열하고 분석했어
대단하다!대단해
좋아뭘 알아냈어?
호흡기 관련 질환의흔적은 없어
시토크롬-C 검사에이 배열이
변칙적이야여기 부분이
각 표본에서구분이 되더라고
다들 다르다고?
그거..그거 이상한데
진짜로찾고있는게 뭐야?
호흡기 질환은 아니지
그래
안녕
왔네!
스캇이쪽은 델피네
안녕
나 수업 빨리가봐야되는데
그래도 이따가좀 들려도 되는지
궁금해서 말야
그럼, 당연하지
알았어
와우! 알았다!
잘있어
잘가
애 깨면요저 금방 돌아올꺼라고
얘기해주세요
그럴꺼냐?
네
아줌마 여기잘 봐주실꺼죠?
헬레나 걱정은하지 말거라
산탄총이요까먹고 있었네요
이나라에 위대한 점중에 하나지..
사냥이 부자들만위한게 아니더라고
저 좀 바쁘거든요아트
빌라도*도 기다릴꺼야, 베스*성경에 예수를 재판한 총독
우리 얘기 좀 해
벌써 다 했잖아요
이번엔 비공식으로
딴 사람 없이
이번이 마지막 기회야
어디 계세요?
있지, 나 충분히눈 못 붙이면
눈가에잔주름 생기거든
내가 금방 너네쇼파로 데려다 줄께
오, 세상에나!
앨리슨
어.. 어떻게 된거에요?이게 뭐에요?
여기 모두들 사랑과 이해의
정신으로 모인인겁니다
부탁이니
함께 하시죠
조정모임에요?
헛짓거리 마세요!
안녕하세요!
필릭스에요게이 친구
연기 코치요
오, 그렇담 여기딱 좋으시군요
어디가요?
예, 예
부디 함께 하세요
앨리슨, 당신의친구분들께서는 오늘
당신과 함께하기 위해그들의 고통과 상처를
한쪽으로 하고 커다란인내심을 보여주셨답니다
음, 도니,모두에 앞서
먼저 시작해주시지않으시겠어요
어..
예
앨리슨
약이나..
음주는
그만 두길 바래
내가 얼마나 힘들었었는지당신은 모르는거 같거든
계속되는 비난에
괴롭힌거나..
구체적으로하셔도 되요, 도니
날 골프채로때렸고
뜨거운 접착제로내 가슴에 화상을 입히고
아직도 목욕할 때면아프다고, 앨리슨
도니..
앨리슨, 지금 당장은사실 그냥 들어만
주시려고 노력하는 것이중요합니다
앤슬리?
앨리슨
네가 내 남편을이용하고
내 결혼까지도망쳐버렸지
날 협박하고공격했지
그래도 진짜로 아픈건네가 우리의 우정에
등을 돌렸다는거라생각해
도니얘기 좀 해라..
엄마!
이게 당신과 나만의문제가 아니야, 앨리슨
우리 애들도 있어
당신 정말 우리 가족이깨져버리길 바래?
앨리슨
2분이에요
2분이라고?
그게 내가, 너하고2년 동안 있던 전부야?
그건 누구에요?
필릭스 도킨스
너 닮은 사람, 사라 매닝의수양 동생이지
예, 그래서요?
몇 주 전에이자 집에 들렸었지
트렁크엔7만5천 달러가 있었고
너 동네 뜨려는거내가 잡았던 날 말야
전부가 매기 첸 총격사건으로되돌아 가고 있어
그러길 바라는거아니시죠, 아트
매기 첸 손에 전화길쥐어준건 선배에요
그게 사고였던 것처럼꾸미는데 도운건 선배라고요
난 내 파트너를도우려고 했던거야
이게 나한테털어놓을
마지막 기회야베스
서로 할 일이나 하죠
사라, 니가 맞았어
내가 틀렸더라
오라, 너 코지마가지고뭘 한거야?
전화한거 분명그애 아니거든
하 하
알았어, 들어봐..
놈들은 우리 DNA로우릴 구분할 수 있어
그걸로 네가 베스가아니란 걸 안거지
그럼 우리가 유전적으로동일하지 않다는거야?
그래야 하는데
인위적인 배열이 있어
이게 정확히 뭔지는모르겠는데
어쨌든, 바코드 같은거지아마
아마 우릴 구분짖는 방법일꺼야머, 그걸로 올리비에가
내가 베스 아니란걸알게된건 설명이 되는데
그래도 리키가내 이름을 어떻게 알았는지설명은 되지 않거든
네가 누군지 안다고?
그래, 거기다 우리가연락하고 있단 것도 알아
델피네한테 무슨얘기한거 아니야?
아니야, 사라아니, 내가..
놈들이 키아라한테한발짝 더 다가온거거든
어..
알았어, 나 절대
너나 키아라 얘기는안했거든
네가 우리 중에서
처음으로 아이를가진 애거든
그러니까복제인간의 자식에
대해선 분류체계조차 없단거야
머, 어쨌거나니가 원하던건 얻었네
나 곧 리키를만날꺼거든
정말로?
기회 한번 줘봐
너 아마도놀랠꺼야
그 사람들우릴 아껴주거든
그 사람들..그래야하고
알았어, 난 그놈 머리에총구를 들이댈 생각이였거든
이런 방지책에죄송합니다
아니, 아니전적으로 이해한다네
안녕, 사라
리키 박사
너도 이 일이 어떻게 된건지정보를 모았겠지
거기엔 나도 대답 못하는많은 질문들이 있단다
그걸로는충분치 않거든요
자네가 짜증나는 것도이해하네만
올리비에나 폴처럼나도 내 부분밖에 모르네
그렇담당신 부분은 뭐죠?
데이타 수집을감독하고
너희의 안녕을계량화 하는거지
난..
난 너희를보살피는거야
난 아니죠
아니지
어떻겐지자넨 빠졌지
세상에 이런..그냥 왜인지나 말해요!
이게 전부뭐하는 거죠?
우리 더 얘기해야지사라
훨씬 많은거
그래도 한가지합의해야 할게 있어
중대한 사항이지
헬레나
공통의 적이지
분명하네
올리비에 말로는 그녀가토마스 얘기를 했다며요. 누구죠?
중요한 질문이네
거기다 내가대답할 수 있기도하고
토마스를 우리 반대세력이야일반적인 과학이지
종교적 극단주의자들이지
프로리씨안*, 그렇게 부르더군 *굳이 해석하면-죽음을 지지하는 자들
그렇네요, 신진화론자가좀 낫네요
수년 전그쪽 요원 하나가
우리 프로젝트에잠입해 들어왔지
매기 첸,베스가 쏜 여자죠
그렇네
그녀와 토마스가수녀원에 있는 헬레나를
찾아내고선, 복제인간이복제인간을 죽이도록 훈련시켰네
영리하지, 정말이야
영리하네요, 정말
그래서, 어떻게요내가 그앨 죽였으면 하세요?
아니지, 우린 전혀그앨 해칠 생각이 없네
자네가 그녈데려와주길 바라지
그럼 우리가재교육시키고
필요한 도움을줄 수 있을꺼네
자네가그렇게 해주면
우리는새로운 이해에서
앞으로 나아갈수 있게되지
자네나 친구들은자네들이 선택한
자유로운 삶을 살게 될껄세감시자도 없고
아, 당신이 우리한테삶을 주시겠다고요?
자네들한테도 항상삶이 있었지
감독 받지는 않았었네관찰만이였지
자네 경우만 빼고
헬레나도요
헬레나는 저쪽보호 아래 있지
우리쪽보다는아주, 아주 안좋다네
그앨 데려오게
그녀한테 필요한도움을 주겠네
안녕, 내 사랑
약속한데로송로와인 가져왔어
너 괜찮지?
너는?
머, 그랬었는데..
델피네 코미에르
베로우아니더라
벌써 면역학에서박사학위도 땄고
아니야?
저..정말..
정말 미안해
내가정말 멍청하지
아니, 아니야
아니야너 안그래
이 모든 걸알아냈잖아
그래, 니가 실수로흘리고간 그 성적표나
파리에 있는가짜 남자친구나
리키 박사가 누군지모르는 척 했던거나
다 헛짓거린지알았지
그래도 네가 계속내편이라고 생각했어
널 믿고 싶었다고
너 나 믿어도 돼
내가 이 여자애들을 안다고리키한테 말했잖아!
그래야했어!
날 봐바
네가 위험에처해있다고 했단말야
무슨 위험?!
모르잖아알어?
몰라
그럼 니가 진짜 위험이네델피네
앨리슨, 너 이러면일만 악화되는거야
나 필릭스하고만말하고 싶어
이거 전부 앤슬리야
그년이 다들끌고 온거지
이것도 전부실험에 일부분이야
그래, 친구들과사랑하는 이들 사이서
망신당하는 의식에서복제인간은 어떻게 반응하는가?
매력적이네
어이!
나도 줄꺼?
어쩌면 앤슬리만이아닐지도
어쩌면 전부가감시자인 거야
목사님은좋아보이시던데
사실 좀섹시한 편이더라
사제복만 입으면그걸로 끝이지
필릭스,나 어떻게 해야될까?
턱 높이 올리고여자가 되는거야
그게 뒤통수치기개론이거든
저기 돌아가지못하겠어
당연히 할 수 있지
나가서 음악을마주하고
맛없는 파이도좀 먹고
껴안아줘쥐죽은 척 하고
앤슬리는 자기가이겼다고 생각할꺼야
그럼 넌 다음 전투까지살아남는거지
오, 이런
나 화장하는거좀 도와줄레?
기쁜 맘으로
헬레나가계속 안받네요
너 어쩔 셈이니
리키한테그앨 넘겨주려고?
모르겠어요
그자가 그애한테정말로
뭘 하려는건지모르겠다고요, 예?
그게 상관은 있니?
그년이 네 딸을쫓아왔는데도
예, 제 속에서는 그년한테총알을 박아주라는데,
이런게 어떤건지이해 못하실 꺼에요
제가 헬레나를 보면제가 보여요
너 걔한테 뭐빚진거 없다, 사라
내가, 음..
내가 영국에 있는사람들한테 연락해 봤다
진짜 니가 어디서온건지 물어봤지
그래서요?
다시 연락주겠다고말은 했는데,
겁을 먹더구나
그쪽에서도 뭔가일어나고 있는 것 같더라
이러지마, 코지마
너 어디로 가려고?
왜, 너보고 리키한테일러바치라고?
내가 진짜 멍청했지!
너 또 무슨 말 했어?
없어!
이름 일곱개뿐이야
키아라 얘긴 안했어
그애 변칙이야너도 알지?
델피네날 이용해도 좋아
그건 괜찮아
하지만, 그 어린 아이근처에도 가면안돼
안그랬어하지도 않을꺼고!
나가!
제발 내 말 들어봐
나 이거 한가지만말할께
그냥 듣기만 해
나 너한테 빠져들고싶지 않았어
그러기로한 것도 아니였고
근데 그래버렸어
내가 어떻게 그 말을믿을 수가 있겠어, 델피네?
너 느끼고 있으니까!
아니야..거짓말 아니야
할 수도 없고
나 예전에 여자랑지내본 적도 없는거 알잖아
그래, 그렇게 보였지
23번, 맞죠?
예, 동쪽 승차장이요북쪽 끝에
제가 다른 쪽에 있었는데탈선기 고정한 쪽이요
저 여자에요
참 안됐어요
베스잖아
그리고는 다른 아가씨가걸어왔죠
저렇게뛰어내렸죠
자, 잠깐요거기 돌려봐요
됐어요.. 그만바로 거기요
젠장
이쪽 각도로는저도 못 봤었네요
헬레나
사라!
내가 진짜 의지할 수있는건 너뿐이거든
함정이 아니라고네가 어떻게 아니?
확실하댔어요
함정이야
어쨌든, 이제 그녀가어딨는지 아니까
그냥 리키한테줘버리는거야
이 점에 대해선저애 말에 동의해야겠구나
그리고 나선요?그땐 리키랑 한편될꺼고
그럼 그자가 키아라에대해 알게 될꺼라고요
사라..
이번엔 저도 어떻게해야될지 모르겠다고요
됐어요? 그냥..잠깐 있어보시라고요
안녕, 너 깼구나
기분은 어떠니?
피곤해요
그래
너 크게 부딪혔단다
그래도 곧괜찮아질꺼야
헬레나 잘못 아니에요
뭐?
제가 아줌마랑놀려고 나갔어요
그렇게 말하라고시킨거니?
아니요
아줌만 위험해
머리 속에 아픈게 있어서우리를 다치게 하려고해
엄마 도움이필요한거에요
미안하다, 키아라
지금은 누구라도 헬레나를도와줄 수 없을거 같구나
앨리슨
네가 채드하고 밴에있었던거 봤어
우리 애들도 봤고
내가 단지 바라는건네가 얼마나 많은 피해를
잃으켰는지이해했으면 하는거야
내 말은, 모두가널 신뢰한다는 거야
앤슬리
오늘 여기 다들네가 데려온거지, 맞지?
나 너 아끼잖니친구야
네가 여기 모두에게연락해서
모든걸 얘기했고
난 널 도와주려고이러는거야
그래서너한테 고마워
내가 이 어항 속으로이사 온 날부터
내 생활 하나하나까지도자세히 봐줘서
넌 나에 대한 소문을캐묻고 염탐해왔지
내가 네 소유물인양,네 개인 실험 대상인 것 처럼
너라면 좋아하겠니?
내가 네 생활을속에서부터 드러내면?
만약 내가 여기 모두한테채드, 네 남편이
나보다 훨씬 전부터자전거 강사하고
잔다는걸 얘기한다거나
또 어쩜 네 남편의그런 행동이
네가 수리공하고그 오두막에서 뽕 빨아서라고!
와우!
됐네요, 음..앨리슨, 당신이 보기..
아니요!
더는 말 마세요!
아내가 맞아요
이제 충분히 했습니다
엄마, 모두들나가세요, 당장!
갑시다
올리브가지*에다가 불을 붙이다니!*화해의 손길
크게 실수한거야
아주 잘 했다
나도 잘한거 같에그래
너 왔네
키아라는 어때?
너 다시는 애못 볼 줄 알아
해치려던건 아니였어
네 말 믿을 수있으면 좋겠다
당겨
젠장!
신경쓰이지?!
아니, 아니야
물러나 있어!
허튼짓 말어!
지금 나한텐네가 전부야
사랑해
네가 사라구나
아이를 해칠 수 없어요!
아일 해친다고?절대 아니다
아이는 순수하단다
네가 바로 빛이다헬레나
네가 바로 원형이지
그말이무슨 뜻이지 아니?
그 아이는 응당네 딸이여야 한다
거짓말이야!헬레나, 헬레나
원형같은건 없어
내가 말했지..우린 다 같에
우리 둘다원형이 아니야
그앨 놔주거라!
우리가 아이를 집에진짜 엄마에게 데려갈꺼다
헬레나! 헬레나
봐, 봐바..
너가 느꼈던연결된 느낌 기억해?
내게도 느껴져
우리 둘이
저여잔 자기 목숨을구하려고 아무말이나 하는거다
저자가 널우리에 가뒀잖아!
저잔 평생동안너한테 거짓말을 했어!
저잔 키아라한테도그렇게 할꺼야
저자는 키아라를다치게 할꺼야
널 다치게한 것처럼
당신이 날이렇게 만들었어
헬레나
니가 뭔지 안다
그렇지, 내가열쇠를 가진 사람이야
어쩌면 열쇠를리키 박사한테 줄꺼고
일어서
사라! 사라!
아줌마?
사라, 너 어딨냐?
헬레나를 리키한테넘기려고요
그잔 내가 누군지 알고키아라에 대해서도
알아내겠죠빠르거나 늦거나요
그러면 안된다
너 곧바로돌아와야겠다
헬레나랑 같이
뭐에요? 왜요?
여기 오거든설명해주마
사라!
나 보자고 했나?
네
베스 차일즈일이에요
죄송해요
여기 있겠다고했었는데요
그래
나타나질 않았어요
당신 생각보다피는 진한거죠, 앨도스
이런 세상에!
아트는 얼마나 오래동안이걸 깔고앉아있었데?
한 이틀 정도됩니다
이러기야, 앤지?
오늘 끝날때까지라고 했잖아
베스 차일즈에게체포영장을 발부할꺼네
부서장님베스 죽었어요
사라 매닝에게영장 내야죠
헬레나는 어딨지?
트렁크에다묶어놨어요
어떻게 된거에요?
사라여긴 아멜리아
안녕하세요
잘 컷네
사라
내가 널 낳은 엄마야
그래, 네가 기대하던사람은 아닐꺼다
기대같은건버렸거든요
이렇게 오게되서미안하구나, 그래도
날 찾는다는얘길 전해들었을 때
서둘러 캐이프타운*을 나왔어야했다*남아프리카공화국 수도
난 감시당하고 있었다이해하지
이렇게 세월이 지나서도놈들이..
놈들이 날 다시찾아냈지
22살 밖에 안됐었지새로운 나라였고
부자 부부가 나한테
시험관 아기 대리모가되달라고 부탁했다
나한테 돈을 주고런던에 잠자리와
법적 절차도 처리해줬지
근데 뭔가 어긋났다
의료검사는 과하게했고
흘려듣기로는 그부부가
의사들을 데려다가
아이를 전통에서벗어나야게 한다고 하더라
무슨 진보된..
진화, 그런거였지
신진화요?
그래, 근데 그들이부부가 전혀 아니였다
과학자들이였지
내가 배고있 아이는그들에게 의미가 없었어
내 안에 있는 생명이위험에 처했다는걸 알게됐다
그래서 도망쳤지
숨어서 몰래너희 둘을 낳은거다
저희 둘이요?
그래, 쌍둥이 였다
너희를 데리고 있지못한다는걸 알았지
그래서 널 숨겨 보냈다..
하나는 기관에다가하나는 교회에다가
헬레나
They knew I wasn't Bethfrom the medical tests.
You said our DNA was identical.
It is. You know, maybe it was
your sunny personality that gave you away.
Who the hell is Maggie Chen?
That's the woman Beth shot.
Maggie helped make you.
Then she saw the light.
Beth killed her to protect us.
Art, you got to see this. It'sa match on the Jane Doe print.
Why the hell does she look like Beth?
Paul... reports to Olivier, his handler.
You just rest and heal.
Dig faster.
Cosima's safety is at stake.
Well, she's not only researching
her own biology,
but she is aware of eight others.
I think he's my watcher.
I think that I may havespotted her real monitor.
You want to mess with my life?
I'm going to mess with yours.
I don't want to divorce Donnie,
but I can't keep lying to him.
So what if we tell them?
Siobhan, this is
Alison Hendrix.
What happened to you?
I don't know.
Kira! Kira, no!
7-year-old femalestruck by a vehicle.
GCS 3,
chest injury, possible internal bleeding.
- Stay with me, baby, please.- 3 minutes.
We're here, love. We're right here.
Let's get her typedand crossed for 3 units.
- We're right here. Please.- Excuse me, excuse me.
This is as far as you go.
No, no, no!
Sarah, Sarah.
We have to let them do their job.
On 3. 1, 2, 3!
I want an ultrasound and a trauma series:
Chest, pelvic, C-spine.Let's get a level 1 on standby
and a crash cart. We may have to intubate.
- O.R.'s being prepped.- Good.
I should've known Helena would find us.
I should've stopped her.
I won't have you blaming yourself.
You did not bring this on.
She's going to be okay, Sarah.
She has to be.
Mm-hmm.
Can I get anybody some coffee?
Alison, I know you mean well,
I know you do, it's just...
Um, I know, I know. I'm in the way.
Yeah.
I just can't help but feel like
it's my daughter in there.
You should go home.
You should get some sleep.
I can't go home, Felix. I...
I assaulted my monitor.
I'm going to get black-bagged like Sarah
and carted off to God knows where.
All right,
use my place, then.
Okay. Thank you.
I'll call you if we hear anything.
Okay.
Ultrasound's up.
Heart rate's at 80.
85/50.
Doctor, you need to see this.
What's happening?
It looks like Kira's going to be okay.
What does "looks like" mean?
Well, she's been sedated,but her blood pressure
and breathing have stabilized.
Her ribs are intact, there's no
internal bleeding, no head trauma.
I think she's gonna be fine.
She was run right over.
I saw it.
Then she's a very lucky girl.
She's okay.
She's okay, she's okay, she's okay.
My baby.
Mummy, she looks like you.
She looks like mummy.
Shh shh shh, shh shh.
Just sleep now, monkey.
I'll keep you safe from her.
I promise.
There was a girl,
a little girl.
Easy, child.
Pull yourself together.
Sarah is a mother.
That's ridiculous!
It's not possible.
The girl was hit by a car because of me.
She's all right?
Yeah, yeah, she's fast asleep.
How about you, then?
Are you thanking your lucky stars?
I don't believe in miracles.
Kids are made of rubber, Sarah.
She got lucky,
just like the doctor said.
You didn't see it.
Count your blessings.
Move on to your worries.
Yeah, Helena's got to go.
I got a dozen reasonsto bring Beth back in.
Look, we got three sets of matching prints,
a jumper who looks just like her,
and we got a smooth little rent-boy
who's connected to them both.
All right, all right. I know, Angie...
And here, we've got Jane Doe,
the one who started it all.
Bet you 100 bucks Iknow who she's looks like
when Beckwith is donewith the reconstruction.
You got no charge that'll stick yet.
Obstruction. This all comes on the heels
- of that civilian shooting.- So what?!
So she could be protecting the killer.
Shh shh shh shh.
How's it going?
Still pushing for a break, sir.
Grigson and Chow just solved
that stabbing in the junction.
Maybe you need
a fresh pair of eyes here, huh?
No, we're good, sir. We're good.
Just give us 'til the end of the day.
You want me to throw
my ex-partner under the bus, hmm?
If I'm wrong about this,
you'll be the last partner I ever have.
I don't know, Art.
I'm starting to wonder.
Does she have something on you?
End of day, Angie.
If this is true,
if the child's actually hers...
How could you let her go?
She's innocent.
I did what I was told...
I used Sarah to get to the others.
Then where are the others?!
Why is Sarah still alive?
That man, Olivier!
- I took off his beast-tail for you.- Yes!
To get Dr. Leekie's attention!
The child will be valuable to them.
No, no!
That's her!
Tell her to come here.
Tell her!
Helena.
Is Kira all right?
I'll tell you in person.
Where are you?
It was an accident.
Tell her!
Lovely apartment for a young couple.
Ahh!
Very convincing.
Unfortunately,
the lie Olivier told last night was not.
What lie?
Someone tampered with thesecurity footage at club Neolution,
but I know there were two clones there
that night, weren't there?
I've searched for the lost clone,
Helena, for years.
She's my white whale, Paul!
But she's feral.
She couldn't fool you,
impersonate Beth,
under this roof,
in that bed.
But Sarah Manning could.
Oh!
What the hell?!
A simple "thank you" would suffice.
So, Kira's going to be okay?
Yes, miraculous recovery.
Okay.
Uh, where's my, um...
Oh, your...
drug paraphernalia is in a drawer.
So is the paraphernaliathat was by your bed.
Did you wash that, too?
My children are at mymother's house right now.
I'm a danger to them.
So I was thinking I could use
this house as a base
while I apartment-hunt.
No!
Well, Donnie's staying clear
of the house for a few hours,
so I just need to go by
and get some sundries and clothing.
Fine! You can stay one night.
Just don't wake me on your way back in.
Felix.
I'm a pariah.
I can't go back there alone.
Mnh!
I need you to be my wingman.
Are you bloody serious?
Please?
I need to change.
Fetch me something gay.
Holy shit, Sarah.
I'm so relieved.
Yeah, even the doctors were stumped.
Do you think, because Kira's mine,
she might be different?
Because she's uninjured?
Yeah, it's just a question.
Well, if they genetically modified us,
I mean, you could've passedsomething down to her.
Like what?
I don't know.
Lizards regrow limbs.
Cosima, Kira's not a lizard.
Right, well,
it's not magic,
it's just stem cells, you know?
Look, I have a guy who's sequencing
the German's DNA alongside mine,
to see if the illness she had was genetic.
If you want, I can give him samples
of you and Kira, to compare.
Yeah, I'm not giving you
our genetic material.
You'd probably hand it over to Delphine.
Dude, I'm just doing what we agreed, okay?
I'm following the science.
Yeah, well,
I worry about scientists more than science.
Got to go.
Eh, I got it.
Hey.
Hey. Coloring books and puzzles.
She's sleeping.
Uh, Mrs S,
this is Paul.
Pleasure.
Paul.
She knows everything.
Well, not everything, clearly.
Well,
don't hold it against me,
but I have some bad news.
Dr. Leekie knows who you are, Sarah.
Let go!
No!
No! No!
I gave you everything!
A reason for living
and, in return... weakness.
Tomas.
No!
If you protect this forgery,
you're no better than they are.
No!
You're no better than they are!
Leekie wants to meet?
He says he wants to make a deal.
He knows you're aware, incontact with each other.
How? Did Cosima give me up?
Look, this is an opportunity.
You sound exactly like her.
I don't trust him, either.
But the genie's out of the bottle.
For them, too.
Your interests havealigned. You can get answers.
Or I could get black-bagged and abducted.
What if there was a way to meet him safely,
on your terms?
Over 4,000 base pairs from each sample,
sequenced and analyzed.
Awesome! Awesome.
Okay, what did you find?
No markers for respiratory disease.
This sequence is anomalous
for cytochrome C and then this piece
is distinct in each sample.
They're different?
That's... that's crazy.
What are you looking for, really?
Not respiratory disease.
Nope.
Hey.
Hey!
Scott, this is Delphine.
Hello.
Hey.
I have to run to class,
but I was wondering if I could
come over later.
Yeah, of course.
Okay.
Oof! Wow! Okay!
Bye.
If she wakes up, just tell her
I'm going to be right back.
And will you?
Yeah.
Are you going to be okay here?
Don't you worry about Helena.
Your shotgun. Forgot about that.
One of the great thingsabout this country...
hunting's not just for the rich.
Kind of busy, here, Art.
Pilates can wait, Beth.
We need to talk.
We already did that.
Off the record, this time.
No one else.
This is your last chance.
Where are you?
You know I get crow's feet
if I don't get enough shuteye.
I will have you backon your couch in a jiff.
Oh, my God!
Alison.
Wh... what's going on? What is this?
We're gathered in a spirit
of love and understanding.
Please,
join us.
An intervention?
This is bullshit!
Hello!
Felix. Gay friend.
Acting coach.
Oh, that's perfectly fine here.
Which one?
Yes, yes.
Please join us.
Alison, your friendshave shown great strength
in setting aside their pain and hurt
in order to talk with you today.
Mm-hmm.
Um, Donnie, why don't you
go ahead and get us started.
Uh...
Yeah.
Alison,
the pills...
and the drinking,
it has to stop.
I don't think you know howhard this has been for me.
The constant criticism,
the abuse.
You can be specific, Donnie.
You hit me with a golf club.
You burned my chest with hot glue.
It still hurts in the shower, Alison.
Donnie...
Alison, it's actuallyimportant for you to just
try and listen right now.
Aynsley?
Alison,
you took advantage of my husband
and may have ruined my marriage, too.
You threatened and assaulted me.
But I think what really hurts is that
you turned your back on our friendship.
Donnie, tell her that we...
Mom!
It's not just about you and me, Alison.
It's about our kids.
Do you really want to break up our family?
Alison.
I have 2 minutes.
2 minutes?
That's all I get, for 2 years by your side?
Who's that?
Felix Dawkins.
Your lookalike, SarahManning's, foster brother.
Yeah, and?
You visited his place a few weeks backwith 75 grand in your trunk,
the day I stopped you from skipping town.
It's all coming back tothe Maggie Chen shooting.
You don't want to go there, Art.
You put the phone in Maggie Chen's hand.
You helped me make it looklike it was an accident.
I was trying to help my partner.
This is your last chance
to come clean with me, Beth.
We do what we gotta do.
Sarah, you were right.
I was wrong.
Okay, what have you done with Cosima?
Because this definitely isn't her.
Ha ha.
Okay, listen...
they can tell us apart by our DNA.
That's how they knew you weren't Beth.
So we're not genetically identical?
We should be,
but there's a synthetic sequence.
I don't know what it is, exactly,
but it's like a barcode, maybe,
- maybe a way to differentiate us?- Well, that explains
how Olivier knew I wasn't Beth,
but it does not explain
how Leekie knows my name.
He knows who you are?
Yeah, and he knows we're in contact.
Did you say something to Delphine?
No. Sarah, no. I...
'Cause they're one step closer to Kira.
Uh...
Okay, I would never
say anything about you or Kira.
You are the first one of us
to ever even have a child.
I mean, there's not even taxonomy
for the offspring of a clone.
Well, either way, you got what you wanted,
'cause I'm about to meet Leekie.
Really?
Just give him a chance.
You might be surprised.
They care about us.
They... they have to.
Yeah, I was thinking ofputting a gun to his head.
Sorry for the precautions.
No no, I understand completely.
Hello, Sarah.
Dr. Leekie.
You've gleaned how this works.
There are many questions I can't answer.
That's not good enough.
I understand your frustration, but,
like Olivier or Paul, I only know my part.
So, what is your part?
I oversee data collection
and quantify your well-being.
I...
I look after you.
Not me.
- No.- Mnh-mnh.
Somehow, you got away.
Jesus Christ. Just tell me why!
What is this all about?
We can go further, Sarah,
much further,
but we need to come to an agreement
on something crucial.
Helena.
A common enemy,
obviously.
Olivier said she mentionedTomas. Who's that?
Great question,
and one I can answer.
Tomas opposes us. Science, in general.
They're religious extremists.
Proletheans, they call themselves.
Right, "Neolutionist" is way better.
Years ago, one of their agents
infiltrated our project.
Maggie Chen, the woman Beth shot.
Yes.
She and Tomas found Helena in a convent,
then trained a clone to kill clones.
Brilliant, really.
That's brilliant, really.
So, what, you want me to kill her?
No, we don't want to harm her at all.
We want you to bring her in
so we can deprogram her,
get her the help she needs.
You do this,
and we can move forward
with a new understanding.
You and your friends will be free
to live as you choose, no monitors.
Oh, you're going to give us lives?
You've always had lives.
They haven't been directed, just observed.
Except in your case.
And Helena's.
Helena's been under their care,
which is far, far worse than ours.
Bring her in.
We'll get her the help she needs.
Bonsoir, ma ch?ie.
I have the truffles that I promised you.
Are you okay?
Are you?
Well, I was, but...
Delphine Cormier,
not Beraud.
You've already got your doctorate
in immunology, don't you?
I am...
so sorry.
I'm so stupid.
No, no,
no, you're not.
You knew this all along.
Yeah, that transcript youaccidentally left behind,
your fake boyfriend in Paris,
pretending you didn'tknow who Dr. Leekie was.
I knew it was bullshit,
but I still thought you were on my side.
I wanted to trust you.
You can trust me.
You told Leekie I know these girls!
I had to!
Look at me.
He says you're in danger.
Of what?!
You don't know, do you?
No.
Then you're the real danger, Delphine.
Alison, you're only making things worse.
I only want to talk to Felix.
This is all Aynsley.
She put them up to this.
It's all part of the experiment.
Yes, how do clones react when ritually
humiliated by friends and loved ones?
Fascinating.
Hey!
Sharesies?
Maybe it's not just Aynsley.
Maybe they're all monitors.
The reverend seems all right.
Actually, he's kind of sexy.
Man of the cloth, and all that.
Felix, what am I going to do?
Put your chin up. Be a woman.
This is backstabbing 101.
I cannot go back out there.
Of course you can.
You're going to face the music,
eat some humble pie,
hug it out, play opossum.
Aynsley's going to think she's won
and you are going tolive to fight another day.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, lord.
Can you help me get my face on?
With pleasure.
Helena still won't answer.
What do you plan to do,
turn her over to Leekie?
I don't know.
I don't know what he's really
going to do with her, do I?
Does that matter?
She came after your daughter.
Yeah, my gut says put abullet in her myself, but,
you don't understand what it's like.
I look at Helena and I see me.
You don't owe her anything, Sarah.
I, um...
I got in touch with mypeople back in England,
about where you're really from.
And?
They said they'd get back to me, but,
they're scared,
as if something isgoing on over there, too.
Please, Cosima.
Where are you going?
Why, so you can tell Leekie?
I'm such an idiot!
What else did you tell him?
Nothing!
Just the seven names.
Nothing about Kira.
She's an anomaly. You know that?
Delphine, you can use me,
that's fine,
but don't go near that little girl.
I didn't and I won't!
Get out!
Please listen to me.
Just let me tell you this one thing.
Just listen to me.
I didn't want to fall for you.
I wasn't supposed to.
But I have.
How can I possibly believe that, Delphine?
Because you feel it!
Ugh!
This is not... it's not a lie.
It's not possible.
You know, I've neverbeen with a woman before.
Yeah, it showed.
The 23rd, right?
Yeah, east platform, north end.
I was on the other side, fixing a derailer.
That's her.
What a shame.
That's Beth.
And then this other lady walks up.
That'd be your jumper.
Wait, wait. Rewind that.
Right... stop, right there.
Shit.
I never saw it from this angle.
Helena.
Sarah!
You're the only one I can really turn to.
How do you know it's not a trap?
She was convincing.
It is a trap.
But now you know where she is,
just give her to Leekie.
I'd have to agree with him, at this point.
And then what? Thenwe're partners with Leekie
and then he's going to find out about Kira.
Tsk. Sarah...
I don't know how I'm going to play this,
okay? Just... just give me a minute.
Hey, you're awake.
How do you feel?
Tired.
Yeah.
You had a big crash,
but you're going to be just fine.
It wasn't Helena's fault.
What?
I went outside to play with her.
She tell you to say this?
No.
She's dangerous.
She's sick in the head andit makes her want to hurt us.
She just needs your help.
I'm sorry, Kira.
I don't think anybody can help Helena now.
Alison,
I saw you in that van with Chad.
My children saw you.
I just wish you could understand
how much damage you've caused.
I mean, we all trusted you.
Aynsley,
you brought us here today, didn't you?
I care about you, sweetie.
You called all these people
and told them everything.
I'm doing this to help you.
And I thank you.
For scrutinizing every detail of my life
since the day I moved into this fishbowl.
You have pried and snoopedand gossiped about me
like I was your own,personal laboratory subject.
How would you like it
if I turned your life inside out?
If I told all these people that Chad,your husband, slept with
the spin-class instructor,
long before me.
Well maybe he acts that way
because you blew the roofer at the cabin!
Wow!
Okay, um... Alison, you see...
No!
No more words!
She's right.
This has gone far enough.
Mom, everybody, out, now!
Let's go.
This was your olivebranch and you torched it!
Huge mistake.
That went very well.
- I think it went well.- Yeah.
You came.
How is Kira?
You're never going to see her again.
I would never hurt her.
I wish I could believe you.
Do it.
Shit!
You care!
No, I don't.
Stay back!
Don't try any shit!
You are all I have now.
I love you.
You must be Sarah.
You can't harm her kid!
Harm her? No, never.
The child is innocent.
You are the light, Helena.
You're the original.
You know what that means?
The child is rightfully your daughter.
- He's lying!- Helena, Helena.
There's no original.
I told you... we're the same.
Neither of us is the original.
Put her down!
We'll bring the childhome to her real mother.
Helena! Helena.
Look, look...
you know that connection you feel?
I feel it, too.
It's us.
She'll say anything to save herself.
He locked you in a cage!
He lied to you your entire life!
He's going to do that to Kira.
He's going to hurt Kira,
like he hurt you.
You made me this way.
Helena.
I know what you are.
Yeah, I'm the one with the keys.
Maybe I'll give 'em to Dr. Leekie.
Come on.
Sarah! Sarah!
S?
Sarah, where are you?
I'm about to give Helena to Leekie.
He knows who I am. He's going to find out
about Kira, sooner or later.
You can't.
You need to get back here, right away.
With Helena.
What? Why?
I'll explain when you get here.
Sarah!
You wanted to see me?
Yeah.
It's about Beth Childs.
I'm sorry.
She said she'd be here.
Yes.
They didn't show.
Blood is thicker than you think, Aldous.
Jesus Christ!
How long has Art been sitting on this?
Just a couple of days, sir.
Really, Angie?
You said by the end of the day.
We're getting an arrestwarrant for Beth Childs.
Lieutenant, Beth's dead.
You need a warrant for Sarah Manning.
Where's Helena?
I tied her up in the trunk.
What's going on?
Sarah, this is Amelia.
Hi.
Look at you.
Sarah.
I'm your birth mother.
Yeah, I'm not what you expected, I'm sure.
I kind of gave up expecting.
I'm sorry to arrive like this, but,
when word came you were looking for me,
I had to leave cape town in a hurry.
I was being watched, you see.
After all this time, they...
they found me again.
I was only 22, in a new country.
A wealthy couple asked me to be
their in-vitro surrogate.
They paid me, provided a flat in London,
a legal arrangement.
But something was off.
The medical tests were excessive
and I overheard the couple
talking with the doctors,
about a child unfettered by tradition,
an advanced...
evolution, of some kind.
Neolution?
Yeah, but they weren't a couple at all.
They were scientists.
The child I carried wasn't meant for them.
I realized the lifeinside of me was in danger,
so I ran,
I hid, and gave birth tothe two of you in secret.
The two of us?
Yeah, I had twins.
I knew I couldn't keep you,
so I hid you away...
one to the state and one to the church.
Helena.
Who do you work for?
I need to see you privately.
I have something for you.
Mind Amelia.
Why?
I found a known associate.
Isn't this place off-limits to you guys?
- Yes?- Alison!
Cosima!
Sarah Manning!